ashp.org 2000-12-06

# ASHP Privacy Statement

## PRIVACY STATEMENT 

for

www.ashp.org

| 

---|---  
  
The American Society of Health-System Pharmacists (ASHP) has created this statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. ASHP is also a licensee of TRUSTe. When you visit a Web site displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, you can expect to be notified of what personally identifiable information of yours is collected and how that information may be shared. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for www.ashp.org. 

**NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES TO PRIVACY STATEMENT**  
Users can find out about changes in this privacy statement by visiting this page. Registered members will be notified via postal mail. This statement was last revised on June 13, 2000. We encourage users to read this statement \- the first TRUSTe-verified statement - thoroughly and use it as a point or reference for the future. 

**COOKIES**   
Our site uses cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. The shopping cart may not perform correctly if the cookies option is turned off in the browser settings. Beginning in early 2000, the site will use cookies to restrict access to some content. ASHP members who elect to brows the site with the cookies option turned off will not be able to access restricted content. 

**LOG FILES**   
Browser type, IP address, access time, and files accessed are collected in log files. ASHP uses this information to analyze traffic on the site and then discards the log files. Aggregate information generated from the log files is sometimes shared with advertisers. 

**PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**   
The site collects personally identifiable information at the following locations: [ASHP Membership Application](http://www.ashp.org/public/memberconst/memberapp.html), [Change of Address Form for ASHP Members](http://www.ashp.org/public/memberconst/cscod.cfm), [Application for PALs Mentors and Protégés](http://www.ashp.org/public/memberconst/pals/index.html), [The ASHP Shopping Cart](https://shop.ashp.org/timssnet/common/tnt_frontpage.cfm), [Communications Center Sign-up](http://www.ashp.org/login/register.cfm), [Listserv sign-up](http://list.ashp.org/scripts/lyris.pl?enter=), and the [CE Testing Center](http://ce.ashp.org/). The information collected includes name, title, home address, business address, e-mail, and credit card number. We use customer contact information from the forms to send orders, newsletters, our journal (AJHP), Products Catalog, and event announcements. A credit card processing company is used to process credit cards. The credit card information is used only for billing purposes. The information we collect is sometimes shared with other reputable organizations to help them contact consumers for marketing purposes. Users may choose to decline receiving future mailings; please see the "Opting Out" section below. Aggregated demographic information may also be compiled and shared, but does not identify the individual user. 

**SPECIAL RELATIONSHIPS**  
Part of the [ASHP Superstore](http://www.doody.com/ashp.htm) is a royalty arrangement with Doody Publishing. Doody Publishing collects personally identifiable information only for billing purposes and never shares personal information with third parties. Doody Publishing does share with ASHP aggregate sales information as part of the royalty arrangement. Please read Doody Publishing's [privacy policy](http://www.doody.com/Rev450WebScripts/aboutPrivacy.asp?ShoppingCartID=0SOCLAB1160840-) for additional information. 

**LINKS**   
This site contains links to other sites. ASHP is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web sites. Please read the privacy statements of the sites to which we link as their privacy practices may differ from www.ashp.org. 

**SURVEY INFORMATION**   
Personally identifiable information is optional in our online surveys and would be used only to contact somebody to clarify an answer. Demographic and profile data that are collected are analyzed and shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis. 

**E-MAIL**   
Throughout this site, users are provided the opportunity to communicate with ASHP via e-mail. We read every message and try to reply promptly to every one. This information is used to reply directly to your questions or comments. Your personal information is only shared with your explicit permission. 

**PUBLIC FORUMS**   
This site makes discussion threads and listserv subscriptions available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information. These forums are moderated and inappropriate messages will be removed. 

**OPTING OUT**   
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from ASHP and any third parties at the point where the information is submitted. Please note that the current ASHP Product Catalog does not provide the user with the opportunity to opt out of mailing lists at this time. 

Users who do not want to receive mailings from ASHP or third parties can contact ASHP by the following means and request to be excluded: 

  1. [Change of Address Form](http://www.ashp.org/public/memberconst/cscod.cfm)
  2. [E-mail](mailto:custserv@ashp.org)
  3. Postal mail:  American Society of Health-System Pharmacists  
7272 Wisconsin Avenue  
Bethesda, MD 20814 
  4. Telephone: (301) 657-4383 

**CHANGING INFORMATION**  
Users have the ability to change information previously provided such as name, address, telephone, and e-mail address. Please contact ASHP by the following means to request the change: 

  1. [Change of Address Form](http://www.ashp.org/public/memberconst/cscod.cfm)
  2. [E-mail](mailto:custserv@ashp.org)
  3. Postal mail:  American Society of Health-System Pharmacists  
7272 Wisconsin Avenue  
Bethesda, MD 20814 
  4. Telephone: (301) 657-4383 

**SECURITY**  
Maintaining the integrity of data collected at www.ashp.org is of utmost important to ASHP. Credit card information is transmitted in encrypted form. Personally identifiable information is stored behind password protection. ASHP has a prudent password rotation policy that is clearly communicated to all staff. Routine backups are made and stored securely. 

**QUESTIONS**   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your use of this Web site, please contact: 

Erik Granered Director, World Wide Web Communications American Society of Health-System Pharmacists 7272 Wisconsin Avenue Bethesda, MD 20814 [egranered@ashp.org](mailto:egranered@ashp.org)
